Jack Fischer

Full-Stack Web Developer

Remote/Miami Beach, FL | <u>letsbuild@jackbuildstech.com</u> <u>https://jackbuildstech.com</u> | <u>https://github.com/sunspla-sh</u>

Summary

I do tech. Visit my personal site https://jackbuildstech.com for a summary of my projects and experience. Everything listed on this resume can also be found on my personal site, which has a better user experience and user interface than this piece of paper... you can also see my video resume here: https://youtu.be/Di2BlgfSh_E

Tech Skills and Theory

Front-End Web Development

JavaScript, Single-page Applications (React), GraphQL, HTML, CSS, SASS, TailwindCSS, Mobile-first (Responsive) Design, D3, GeoJSON, TopoJSON, JSON, XML, Vite, Chrome Extensions (CRXJS), npm, pnpm, Open Graph Protocol, Websockets (Socket.io)

Back-End Web Development

Node.js, Web Application Frameworks and APIs (Express), Databases (MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQLite), ODMs and ORMs (Mongoose, Sequelize, Prisma), GraphQL, Unit Testing (Jest), Puppeteer, Nodemailer, Email Templating (Handlebars), Websockets (Socket.io), MVC architecture, npm, pnpm

DevOps and Tooling

Version Control (Git), CI/CD (TravisCI), Cloud Infrastructure (DigitalOcean, AWS, Fly.io, Heroku), Docker, Kubernetes, Linux, Monorepos, Bundlers and Build Systems (TurboRepo, Rollup), Postman

Experience

Full Stack Web Development Instructor

March 2022 - January 2023

Ironhack (https://ironhack.com)

 My former students collectively earn roughly \$800,000-1,000,000 in annual income as junior web developers (or similar tech jobs) with an average salary in the \$50,000-60,000 range (representing a 50-100% increase in annual income for most of them, because they primarily came

- from a hospitality or retail service background)
- Taught 4 cohorts of students to use modern, full stack web development technologies such as the following: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Mobile-first (Responsive) Design, Express, Handlebars, Databases (MongoDB), ODMs (Mongoose), Single-page Applications (React), Version Control (Git and Github), Unit Testing (Jest), Deployment, etc.

Failed Startups - Multiple Attempts Failed Startups

September 2021 - February 2022

- Rejected from YCombinator with first moonshot idea converting dry oil wells to geothermal wells the idea was capital-intensive and we had no
- Continued on solo with second idea scuba diving booking software-as-a-service I tried to be smarter this time and pre-sell based on UX/UI wireframes before building it, but failed to find product-market fit (basically I ran out of savings)

clear path forward (and no cash), so my co-founders returned to their jobs

Gap Year - Spanish Language

August 2020 - August 2021

Playa Del Carmen (Mexico), Austin TX, Denver CO, Salt Lake City UT

- Studied Spanish in Mexico to a tested level of CEFR Level B1 Intermediate (Level B1 is high enough to gain entrance to some
 universities in Spain such as <u>Universidad Complutense Madrid</u> while
 others require B2)
- Spanish exam credential can be independently verified at the following website (https://siele.org/en/comprobar-certificado) using my credential ID: li3knEHpdbkjrFuagvJ7RA==
- Learned to scuba dive and earned both Open Water and Advanced Open Water Diver certifications through PADI (Professional Association of Diving Instructors)
- Tried living in various US cities (1-2 months per city) to determine if I wanted to settle in any of them long-term

Front-End Web Developer (Contractor)

April 2019 - July 2020

Carnival Cruise Line (https://carnival.com)

- Built various front end sections of the carnival.com site including updated versions of the checkout review page within the booking engine, mobile menu, modals, banners, sliders etc
- A/B tested code and toggled features using Optimizely to verify that newly coded sections of the site increased overall customer conversions/revenue

Projects

1) JobAppTrack (https://jobapptrack.com)

(https://github.com/sunspla-sh/simple-job-app-tracker-react)

As a coding bootcamp instructor, I saw my students struggle to apply for jobs and track their stages in the interview process. I built this job application tracker web app and chrome extension for them using modern web technologies.

Technologies Used:

Docker, Vite, React, CSS, JavaScript, Prisma, SQLite, Node.js, Express, Nodemailer, Handlebars, Open Graph Protocol, CRXJS, pnpm, TurboRepo, Socket.io (Websockets), Fly.io

2) GitBoxDraw (https://gitboxdraw.com)

(https://github.com/sunspla-sh/github-commit-text-generator)

This app allows you to create art with your Github commit graphs by selecting individual git commit dates from a user interface. It then auto-generates a bash script which you can run in your terminal to create the desired commits, which you can then push to a Github repository.

Technologies Used:

Vite, Sass, HTML, JavaScript, Open Graph Protocol, Node.js, Rollup, JavaScript Obfuscator (Rollup Plugin), npm, DigitalOcean

3) IPomg (https://ipomg.com)

(https://github.com/sunspla-sh/ipomg-static)

Find your IP address and approximate geolocation with this static site and free API. My goal with this project was to try out TailwindCSS (which exploded in popularity over the past couple of years) and also Maxmind's free GeoLite2 geolocation database.

Technologies Used:

Vite, TailwindCSS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MaxMind GeoLite2 DB, Node.js, Express, npm, DigitalOcean

4) CommandLineCartography

(https://github.com/sunspla-sh/command-line-cartography-practice)

Learn to make a population density map of your state. The Github repository contains a condensed set of instructions and commands. There's a much larger and more detailed tutorial written by @mbostock on Medium.com,

who originally created the process for the state of California, which I later adapted for Florida.

Technologies Used:

D3, GeoJSON, TopoJSON, pnpm, U.S. Census Bureau Data

5) S Tier Web Dev

(https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLgF6apjFR90209B4006e8gpNV7qUC-bUD)

Video lessons covering the basics of web development on YouTube and a course website using Podia. Currently ~30 lessons are finished (and free) out of several hundred planned lessons. The lesson creation process is time-intensive, requiring ~4 hours of work to yield ~10 minutes of high-quality video. I started the project in January 2023 and my 1-2 year goal for the project is to cover modern web theory and tech from beginner HTML, CSS and JavaScript through more advanced enterprise-grade technologies like Docker and Kubernetes.

Technologies Used:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Various Recording and Editing Software (Kdenlive, OBS, GIMP. YoutubeStudio. Podia)

6) NFL Team Data Scraper (https://github.com/sunspla-sh/nfl-team-data-scraper)

One of my former web development bootcamp students needed NFL team data for a project. I created this scraper to collect the data, because we couldn't find free data online in the format that they wanted. NFL.com is a single-page application that loaded team data asynchronously, so I needed to use Puppeteer (a headless web browser) to detect events and then scrape after a delay when the page was ready.

Technologies Used: Puppeteer, Node.js, npm

Other Skills

Languages:

English (Native),

Spanish (CEFR - Level B1 - SIELE - <u>Credential ID li3knEHpdbkjrFuagvJ7RA==</u>), Russian (CEFR - Level A1)

Video and Image Editing:

Kdenlive (Video Editing), OBS (Video recording and livestreaming) GIMP (Image Editing)

Education

Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp - Ironhack

Jan 2019 - Mar 2019

10-week intensive (400+ hour) web development boot camp which complimented my existing computer science skills from some of my university classes

Study Abroad - Moscow State University

May 2016 - Aug 2016

This is less cool nowadays because of the fighting and so on... but it was fun at the time. I studied Russian language and culture during summer break and visited various cities in Russia.

Liberal Studies, B.A. - Iowa State University

Aug 2014 - Jun 2018

I paid too much money for an arguably worthless piece of paper. Fortunately, younger me decided to fill some elective classes with computer science subjects. Unfortunately, they were taught in Java.